Finding Aid for New World State Wide V’s Realty Michigan real estate publications, 1973-2011
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
New World State Wide V’s Realty Michigan real estate publications
1973-2011
New World State Wide V’s Realty, collector
2011110 Aa 2
New World State Wide V’s Realty’s collection of Michigan real estate data and sales books for Albion County (1997-2003), Hillsdale County (1995-1999), Jackson County (1994-2009), Lenawee County (1993-2007, and 2010), Monroe (1988, 1993-1994, and 1996-2009), Washtenaw County (1973-2011), and Wayne County (1976-1982, 1985, and 1988-2004).
21.3 linear feet in 22 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by New World State Wide V’s Realty (Donor no. 10583 ) in June 2011
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
New World State Wide V's Realty opened in 1978 in Ypsilanti, Michigan, serving the city of Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County, Monroe County, Lenawee County and surrounding areas. Services include real estate listings, multi-family assistance, condo listings, selling and buying homes, vacant lots, among others. While the agency focuses on residential areas, it provides assistance on minor commercial properties.
The New World State Wide V's Realty property listings and sales book collection contains materials for Albion, Hillsdale, Lenawee, Monroe, parts of Oakland, Washtenaw, and Wayne Counties of the state of Michigan. Materials are arranged in alphabetical order by county and in chronological order within each county.
Materials for the Washtenaw County contain a number of types of publications --comparable sales books, data books, and Real Estate Pace summary reports. Depending on the time period, materials were published separately or jointly by Ypsilanti Board of Realtors and Ann Arbor Board of Realtors, or by the Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors. Due to this complexity, Washtenaw County materials are arranged in strict chronological order, with each box containing all available materials produced by different boards for the same areas and years.
Publications for Wayne County arranged by area or Realty Board and in chronological order within each area.
Collection also includes Women's Council of Realtors Roster (1978) and 1 folder containing materials of the KWS Realty (Ann Arbor and Southfield) with descriptions of several commercial properties in Ann Arbor (1991).
Subjects:
Real estate business--Michigan--Albion.; Real estate business--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Real estate business--Michigan--Calhoun County.; Real estate business--Michigan--Hillsdale County.; Real estate business--Michigan--Jackson County.; Real estate business--Michigan--Lenawee County.; Real estate business--Michigan--Monroe County.; Real estate business--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Real estate business--Michigan--Wayne County.; Real estate listings--Michigan.; Real property--Listing--Michigan.; Albion (Calhoun County, Mich.)--Commerce.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Commerce.; Calhoun County (Mich.)--Commerce.; Hillsdale County (Mich.)--Commerce.; Jackson County (Mich.)--Commerce.; Lenawee County (Mich.)--Commerce.; Monroe County (Mich.)--Commerce.; Washtenaw County (Mich.)--Commerce.; Wayne County (Mich.)--Commerce.
Contributors:
New World State Wide V's Realty.
- Calhoun County
  - Sold properties catalog, December 1997-June 2003 (Box 1)
  - Computerized multiple listings, February-October 2003 (Box 1)
- Hillsdale County
  - Sold properties, April 1995-September 1999 (Box 1)
  - Comparable listings digest, January 1999-September 2002 (Box 1)
  - Comp book, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Comp book, 2003-2008 (Box 2)
  - Hillsdale County Board of Realtors Board Bylaws, 2007 (Box 2)
  - Hillsdale County Board of Realtors Multiple Listing Service Bylaws, Rules, and Regulations, 2007 (Box 2)
- Jackson County
  - Comparable book, 1994-1996 (Box 2)
  - Comparable book, 1997-2001 (Box 3)
  - Sold volume, 2002-2004 (Box 3)
  - Volume sold, 2005 (Box 3)
  - Volume sold, 2006-2009 (Box 4)
- Lenawee County
  - Comparable book, January 1993-October 1996 (Box 4)
  - Comparable activity digest, October 1996-December 2001 (Box 4)
  - Sold volume
    - 2002-2004 (Box 5)
    - April-September 2005 (Box 5)
  - Volume sold
    - 2006 (Box 5)
    - January-June 2007 (Box 5)
    - January-March 2010 (Box 5)
- Monroe County
  - Semi-annual Pace report (revised), July-December 1988 (Box 5)
  - Comparable book
    - 1993 (Box 5)
    - January-March 1994 (Box 5)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 5)
  - Listings of properties available for sale
    - 1998-2000 (Box 5)
    - January-March 2001 (Box 5)
  - Year to date, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Comparable sales book, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Sold volume, 2002-2004 (Box 5)
  - Volume sold, 2005-2009 (Box 6)
- Oakland County, Southeast
  - The Real Estate Pace Summary, March 1989 (Box 6)
- Washtenaw County
  - Ypsilanti Board of Realtors property listings by street, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Ypsilanti Board of Realtors Comparable, February-December 1974 (Box 6)
  - Ypsilanti Board of Realtors Comparable
    - 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - March-June 1977 (Box 6)
  - Ann Arbor Board of Realtors multiple listing, September 12, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Comparable Yearbooks, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, Part 2, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Comparable Sales Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1980 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Comparable Sales Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1982 (Box 8)
  - Comparable Sales Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, January-September 1982 (Box 8)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Comparable Sales Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1983 (Box 8)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, Photo and Index sections, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Comparable Sales Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Comparable Sales Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors and Ypsilanti Boards of Realtors, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Washtenaw County Properties multiple listing, Ann Arbor Board of Realtors, July 30, 1987 (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1987; April-June 1988 (Box 9)
  - The Real Estate Pace Summary Report, August-December 1989 (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Real Estate Pace Summary Report, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1991 (Box 9)
  - The Real Estate Pace Summary Report, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1993 (Box 10)
  - The Real Estate Pace Summary Report, 1993 (Box 10)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1994 (Box 10)
  - The Real Estate Pace Summary Report, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1995 (Box 10)
  - The Real Estate Pace Summary Report, 1995 (Box 10)
  - Washtenaw County Properties Data Book, Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors, 1996 (Box 10)
  - The Real Estate Pace Summary Report, July-October 1996 (Box 10)
  - Ann Arbor Area Board of Realtors Data Book
    - 1997 (Box 11)
    - January-June 1998 (Box 11)
    - 1999-2003 (Box 11)
    - July-September 2004 (Box 11)
    - 2005-2006 (Box 12)
    - (Parts 1-2), 2007 (Box 12)
    - (Parts 3-4), 2007 (Box 13)
    - 2008 (Box 13)
    - January-September 2009 (Box 13)
    - 2010 (Box 13)
    - January-March 2011 (Box 13)
- Wayne County
  - U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development selling list photo sold book, Detroit and Flint, January-September 1976 (Box 14)
  - Comparable Yearbook A, Downriver Board of Realtors, December 1977-November 1978 (Box 14)
  - Comparable book, Downriver Board of Realtors
    - January 21-May 31 and December 1979 (Box 14)
    - March-August 1980 (Box 14)
    - December 1 1980-May 1981 (Box 14)
  - Comparable book, Down River Board of Realtors
    - December 1981-November 1982 (Box 14)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 14)
  - Comparable book, Down River Board of Realtors
    - 1990-1995 (Box 15)
    - 1996-2000 (Box 16)
    - March-September 2001 (Box 16)
  - Metro MLS Commercial, August 23, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Metro MLS, November 4, 1985
    - April-December 1989 (Box 17)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 17)
  - Metro MLS Comparable book, 1992-1993 (Box 18)
  - Western Wayne County (title missing from the original), July 1, 1980 (Box 18)
  - Western Wayne County/Dearborn Sold information, 1994-1997 (Box 19)
  - Western Wayne County/Dearborn Sold information, 1998-2000 (Box 20)
  - Western Wayne County/Dearborn Regional multiple listing book
    - Week of, July 19, 2000 (Box 20)
    - Week of, December 20, 2000 (Box 20)
  - Western Wayne County/Dearborn Sold information
    - January-November 2001 (Box 21)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 21)
    - April-October 2004 (Box 22)
- Miscellaneous publications
  - Women's Council of Realtors Roster, 1978 (Box 22)
  - KWS Realty commercial real estate records, 1991 (Box 22)